以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，如果你想知道的话，那就去吧
okay let's go so if you want to know the
今天的班斧它等于B的主题
subject of today's class its ax equal B
我开始写不同的了
I got started writing down different
斧头等于B的可能性我得到了
possibilities for ax equal B and I got
走开了
carried away
它只是出现了
there's it just appears all over the
地方和四种不同的大小
place and the four different sizes
不同级别的不同情况
different ranks different situations
几乎奇异而不是单数和
nearly singular not nearly singular and
问题是你在每个方面做了什么
the question is what do you do in each
我可以概述一下我的小二
case so can I outline my little two
这里的笔记页然后选择一个
pages of notes here and then pick on one
或者今天要开发的其中两个主题
or two of these topics to develop today
多一点上周五约
and a little more on Friday about
克施密特所以我不会做太多的事情
gram-schmidt so I won't do much of much
如果有任何克施密特今天，但我会
if any of gram-schmidt today but I will
做其他人没关系
do the others okay
所以问题是斧头等于B
so the problem is ax equal B that
问题来自我们所拥有的某个地方
problem has come from somewhere we have
产生某种答案X好吧
to produce some kind of an answer X okay
所以我有点从好到坏
so I'm sort of going from good to bad or
这份清单中的好或难
good or easy to difficult in this list
很好，除了数字零，这是
so well except for number zero which is
在所有情况下使用的答案
an answer in all cases the using the
我最后介绍的伪逆
pseudo-inverse that I introduced last
时间，以便处理零特征值
time so that deals with zero eigenvalues
和零奇异值说
and zero singular values by saying
他们是逆也是0，这是善良的
they're inverse is also 0 which is kind
狂野的，所以我们会回来的
of wild so we'll come back to the
伪逆的意义，但现在
meaning of the pseudo inverse but now
我想在这里变得真实
I'm I want to get real here about
第一个是不同的情况
different situations so number one is
一个人有一个好的正常情况
the good normal case when a person has a
合理大小的方阵
square matrix of reasonable size
合理状态的条件
reasonable condition the condition
数字o我应该的条件数
number o the condition number I should
称之为Sigmaone
call it Sigma one
在Sigmañ它是最大的比例
over Sigma n it's a ratio of the largest
到最小的奇异值和让我们
to the smallest singular value and let's
说这个理由不超过一个
say that's within reason not more than a
一千或一些正常
thousand or something then normal
普通淘汰将会起作用
ordinary elimination is going to work
和MATLAB的命令会
and MATLAB the command that would
产生答案只是反斜杠但是
produce the answer is just backslash but
所以现在这是正常情况的情况下
so this is the normal case now in cases
一些跟随或有问题
that follow or have problems of some
亲切的，我想我希望这是
kind and I guess I'm hoping that this is
什么是有用的字典
a sort of useful dictionary of what to
为你和我做的都好，所以我们
do for for you and me both okay so we
我们也有这种情况
have this case here where we have too
许多方程式因此非常正常
many equations so it's a pretty normal
案例，这是我们主要想到的
case and it's the we'll think mostly of
用最小二乘法解决这个问题
solving by least squares which leads us
这是正常的等式
to the normal equation so this is
标准一直在发生
standard happens all the time in
统计和我想的
statistics and I'm thinking in the
合理的情况就是这样
reasonable case so that's that would be
X解决方案一转这个
X hat the solution a transfer this this
矩阵是可逆的
matrix would be invertible and
合理的大小，所以我们可以
reasonable size so we could actually
反斜杠仍然可以解决这个问题
backslash would still solve that problem
反斜杠不需要正方形
backslash doesn't require a square
矩阵给你一个答案，这样就可以了
matrix to give you an answer so that's
你会这样做的好例子
that's the good case where you would
只是矩阵不是太大，所以它的
just the matrix is not too big so it's
形成转置并不是不合理的
not unreasonable to to form a transpose
好吧现在还有另一个极端
a okay now there is the other extreme
对我们来说令人兴奋的是这样的
and like what's exciting for us is so
这是我不知道的欠定情况
this is the underdetermined case I don't
有足够的方程，所以我必须把
have enough equations so I have to put
更具体的东西
something more in to get a specific
回答以及让我们感到兴奋的是什么
answer and what makes it exciting for us
这是深度学习的典型
is that that's typical of deep learning
深沉的重量如此之多
there are so many weights in a deep
神经网络的权重将
neural network that the weights would be
未知数
the unknowns
它不一定是线性的
it wouldn't be necessarily linear
不是线性的，但仍然是这个想法
wouldn't be linear but still the idea is
同样我们有很多解决方案
the same that we we have many solutions
我们必须选择一个或我们必须
and we have to pick one or we have to
选择一个算法，然后它会找到
pick an algorithm and then it will find
一个，所以我们可以选择最低限度
one and so we could pick the minimum
规范解决方案最短的解决方案
norm solution the shortest solution that
将是一个l2答案或我们可以去
would be an l2 answer or we could go to
l1和我认为的一个大问题
l1 and a big question that's I think
可能在2018年定居的确很深
might be settled in 2018 is does deep
学习和迭代
learning and the iteration from
随机梯度下降，我们将
stochastic gradient descent that we'll
很快就会看到它
see soon pretty soon does it go to the
最小L什么它挑选了l1
minimum L what does it pick out an l1
解决方案，这真的像一个
solution that that's really like an
你知道的令人兴奋的数学问题
exciting math question you know for a
很长一段时间，它有点标准
long time it was sort of standard to say
这些深度学习的AI代码是
these deep learning AI codes are
太棒了，但他们在做什么呢
fantastic but what are they doing we
不知道
don't know
你知道内部但我们何时何地
you know the interior but where we when
我说我们并不是说其他人
I say we I don't mean I other people are
到那里，我会告诉你的
getting there and I'm gonna tell you as
当我们到达那里时，就像我能做到的那样
much as I can about it when we get there
好的，这些都很标准
okay so that's those are pretty standard
情况M等于N且大于它们M.
cases M equals N and greater than them M
不到n但不疯狂现在让
less than n but not crazy okay now let
我第二板会有更多
me the second board will have like more
困难的问题通常是因为
difficult problems where usually because
它们在某种程度上几乎是单数的
they're nearly singular in some way the
列几乎是依赖的好吧
columns are nearly dependent okay so
寻找那将是的列
look for that would be the columns in
糟糕的情况你刚刚挑选了一个可怕的
bad condition you just picked a terrible
基础或性质做了或不知何故你
basis or nature did or somehow you've
得到一个列为a的矩阵
got a matrix a whose columns are
实际上几乎线性地依赖
virtually dependent almost linearly
依赖逆矩阵是真的
dependent the inverse matrix is really
但它存在的时候就是你
but it exists then that's when you you
进去，你修复了你的列
go in and you fix the columns you
地正交列，而不是
orthogonalize columns instead of
接受a1a2到a的列
accepting the columns a 1 a 2 up to a n
你进去的给定矩阵和你
of the given matrix you go in and you
在其中找到正交列向量
find orthonormal column vectors in that
列空间正交基Q1到
column space an orthonormal basis Q 1 to
将q个n和两个由连接
Q n and the two are connected by
克施密特和着名的矩阵
gram-schmidt and the famous matrix
克施密特的声明就在这里
statement of gram-schmidt is here are
这里的列是列的列
the columns of a here are the columns of
Q并且有一个三角矩阵
Q and there's a triangular matrix that
连接两者，这是一个中心
connects the two so that is a central
主题克-施密特在那个想法中
topic gram-schmidt in that idea of
正交Ising它刚刚出现
orthogonal Ising it just appears
到处都是六对
everywhere pairs all over course six in
与许多不同的情况很多
many many situations with different
这些名字让我有点拯救了
names so that I'm sort of saving a
一点点，直到下一次，让我
little bit till next time and let me
告诉你为什么因为只是
tell you why because just the
格拉姆-施密特的组织
organization of gram-schmidt is
有趣的是你可以做的克施密特
interesting so gram-schmidt you could do
正常的方式，这就是我教的内容
the normal way so that's what I teach in
1806就这样只需要每一列
1806 just just take every column as it
自带减去关闭突起到
comes subtract off projections onto
他们以前的东西让它正交
their previous stuff get it orthogonal
以前的人归它是
to the previous guys normalize it to be
一个单位向量然后你就有了
a unit vector then you've got that
专栏继续说再说再说
column go on sorry say that again and
然后我会再过两天再说一遍
then I'll say it again two days from now
所以克施密特的想法是你拿走了
so gram-schmidt the idea is you take the
你说第二列的列是
columns you you say the second column is
一些常见的第二正交矢量Q2
some common second orthogonal vector Q 2
将是第一列的一些组合
will be some combination of columns one
和两个正交于第一个ya
and two orthogonal to the first ya
什么是欲望，而且有
what's lust to do and and there's
另一个真正的订单
another order which is really
更好的命令做克-施密特和
the better order to do gram-schmidt and
它允许你进行列旋转
it allows you to do column pivoting so
这是我下次要看的主题
this is my topic for next time to see
克-施密特更加认真对待
gram-schmidt more carefully right
好吧是的列旋转意味着你
okay yeah column pivoting means you
让自己带你去
allow yourself to take the you the
列可能不是很好
columns might not come in a good order
所以你允许自己重新排序我们
so you allow yourself to reorder them we
知道你有这样做的
know that you have to do that for
消除权利和消除权利
elimination right and in the elimination
这将是行，所以消除我们会
it would be rows so elimination we would
有一个矩阵a和它我们采取的
have a the matrix a and its we take the
第一行作为第一个枢轴行和
first row as the first pivot row and
然后是第二行，然后是第三行
then the second row and then the third
行，但如果枢轴是如此，如果
row but if the pivot is so that if the
pivot太小并重新排序行
pivot is too small and reorder the rows
所以这是它自带的行排序
so it's it's its row ordering that comes
在消除和你很好的MATLAB
up in elimination and you well MATLAB
只是系统地说好的就是
just systematically says okay that's the
枢纽即将成为第三个支点
pivot that's coming up the third pivot
出现了第三排，但MATLAB的
comes up out of the third row but MATLAB
说看看整个第三列
says look down that whole third column
为了更好的枢轴更大的枢轴开关
for a better pivot a bigger pivot switch
我们做一排交换所以有
do we do a row exchange so there are
大量排列的，那么你最终会
lots of permutations then you end up
那里有一些东西可以让人感觉到
with a something there that permutes the
这被计入行，然后
rows and then that gets factored into
列欧，所以我说的是关于
Leu so I'm saying something that about
消除那种只是偏执的一面
elimination that that just sort of side
评论你永远不会做
comment that you you would never do
消除而不考虑
elimination without considering the
行交换的可能性然后
possibility of row exchanges and then
这是
this is
克-施密特正交化所以这个
gram-schmidt orthogonalization so this
这里的Lu世界是QR世界和
is the Lu world here's the QR world and
这恰好是那列
here it happens to be columns that
你正在通勤，以便即将到来
you're commuting so that's coming that
这是第2.2节，但有更多
this is section 2.2 but there's more a
2.2中有相当多的内容
2.2 has quite a bit in it including
数字0伪逆和
number 0 the pseudo-inverse and
包括一些这些东西实际上
including some of these things actually
这也将是2.0，也许这个
this will be also in 2.0 and maybe this
就是我今天想说的更多
is what I'm like saying more about today
所以这将成为一个小明星
so this would be a put a little star for
今天你在这做什么，这是一个
today here what do you do so this is a
矩阵几乎是单数的情况
case where the matrix is nearly singular
你是危险的，它是逆的
you're you're in danger its inverse is
会变得无比大而我
gonna be big unreasonably big and I
写了反问题，因为
wrote inverse problems there because
反问题就是这种类型
inverse problem is that's a type of
你需要申请的问题
problem that you need application that
你经常需要解决，或者你的
you often need to solve or that you the
工程和科学有
engineering and and science have to
解决
solve
所以我再说一点
so I'll just say a little more about
但这是一个典型的应用程序
that but that's a typical application in
你得到你的近乎单一的你的
which you get your near singular your
矩阵不够好，无法很好地反转
matrix isn't good enough to invert well
你当然可以说得好
of course you could over say well I'll
只是用伪逆但是这
just use the pseudo inverse but that's
在数字上，这就像欺骗你一样
numerically that's like cheating you've
得到你必须进入那里做
got a you got to get in there and do
关于它的事情
something about it
所以反问题就是例子
so inverse problems would be examples
实际上，正如我写的那样，我认为
actually as I write that I think that
将是我应该添加的主题
would be a topic that I should add that
到a的潜在主题列表
to the list of potential topics for a
一个为期三周的项目来查找
for a three week project to look up a
关于反问题的书，我该怎么办？
book on inverse problems so what do I
我只是反问题的意思
mean by the inverse problem I'll just
完成这个想法在哪里
finish this thought where of what's an
逆问题通常你就是你
inverse problem typically you you you
知道他们的系统说网络
know about their system say a network
喜欢尝试
like trying to
RLC网络，你给它一个电压或
RLC Network and you give it a voltage or
当前你给它一个输入和你
a current you give it an input and you
找到你发现的输出
find the output you find out what
电流流过电压但是
current flows what the voltages are but
你知道反问题
inverse problems are suppose you know
对不同电压的响应是什么
the response to different voltages what
是你看到的网络是什么
were the what was the network you see
问题让我再说一遍
that the problem let me say it again
发现网络的来源
discover what the network is from its
输出通常是结果
outputs so that turns out to typically
是一个几乎奇异的问题
be a problem that gives nearly singular
这是一个困难的矩阵
matrices that's that's a difficult
你附近很多附近的问题
problem you sort of near a lot of nearby
网络实际上也是如此
networks would give virtually the same
输出所以你有一个矩阵
output so so you have a matrix that's
它几乎是奇异的，它具有奇异的价值
nearly singular it's got singular values
非常接近零，你做什么呢
very close to zero what do you do then
以及反问题的世界
well the world of inverse problems
一些加入了惩罚项的认为
thinks of adding a penalty term some
当我最小化的时候，这是一种惩罚
kind of a penalty term when I minimize
这件事本身就是平常的
this thing just by itself in the usual
转置a的方式有一个巨大的反转
way a transpose a has a giant inverse
矩阵a严重受制于它
the matrix a is badly conditioned it
将矢量Verge几乎变为零
takes vectors Verge almost to zero so
转置a是一个巨人
that a transpose a is has got a giant
反过来你就是冒险了
inverse and you're you're at risk of
因为你失去了一切
losing everything to roundoff so you
这是你可以称之为的解决方案
this is the solution you could call it a
一种廉价的解决方案，但它
kind of cheap solution but it's
每个人都使用它，所以我不会这样做
everybody uses it so I won't put that
关于录像带的话，但那就是那种
word on videotape but that that sort of
解决问题，但问题
resolves a problem but then the question
无论如何它转移了一个问题-什么
it it shifts a problem anyway - what
数字应该是什么惩罚如何
number what should be the penalty how
你应该多惩罚它，你会看到它
much should you penalize it you see as
你在购买时添加它
you as you buy adding that
你会让它变得可逆，如果
you're gonna make it invertible and if
你做得越来越大了
you make this bigger and bigger and
更大的是越来越好
bigger it's more and more well
条件它解决了这里的麻烦
conditioned it resolves the trouble here
我就是这样，这是像今天我要去
and I'm so this is like today I'm gonna
做更多的事情让我停下来
do more with that so that I'll stop
还有，说以后把它捡起来
there and pick it up after saying
约6和7的东西
something about 6 & 7
我希望这对你有帮助
I hope this is helpful it was helpful to
我当然要看到这些
me certainly to to see all these
可能性并写下一些
possibilities and to write down sort of
你的症状是什么，就像一个
what you what the symptom is it's like a
医生等的线性方程医生
doctor like a linear equation doctor
就像你寻找症状然后
like you look for the symptoms and then
你在CVS提出了一些建议
you propose some some something at CVS
这有效或无效，但你做到了
that works or it doesn't work but you do
一些事情好了，所以当
something about it okay so so when the
问题太大所以到现在为止
problem is too big so up to now the
问题并没有成为巨大的问题
problems have not been giant out of
当然是这样，但现在它太大了
course it's so but now when it's too big
好吧也许它仍然在Corbett
well maybe it's still in Corbett really
大，然后这是2.1所以这是
big then this is in 2.1 so that's to
回到我能说的话
come back to the word I could have
写在这里如果我要去
written in here if I was just gonna
写一个字就是互动
write one word would be interation
迭代方法意味着你拿一个
iterative methods meaning you take a
像共轭梯度法一样的步骤
step like well conjugate gradient method
是迭代方法的英雄
is the is the hero of iterative methods
然后那里我参加比赛的名字就是
and then there that name I raced is
克里洛夫还有其他名字
Krylov and there are other names
与迭代方法相关联
associated with iterative methods so
这是我们通过的部分
that's the section that we passed over
只是为了滚动，但我们会来
just just to get rolling but we'll come
回到那么那个你永远不会
back to so then that that one you never
得到确切的答案，但你越来越近了
get the exact answer but you get closer
更接近
and closer
如果迭代方法成功
if the iterative method is successful
就像你得到的共轭梯度一样
like conjugate gradients you get
非常接近很快，然后你
pretty close pretty fast and then you
说好的我会接受的
say okay I'll take it
然后最后太大了就像没有
and then finally way too big like no
我们不是在核心只是你的矩阵你
we're not in core just your matrix you
只是有一个巨巨问题，其中
just have a giant giant problem which of
当然，正在发生的这些天，然后
course is happening these days and then
一种方法是你我的矩阵
one way to do it is your matrix you I
意思是你，你甚至可以不看的
mean you you can't even look at the
矩阵不是一个转置a
matrix a much less a transpose a
转置一个就像是不可想象的
transpose a would be like unthinkable
你不能在a中做到这一点
you couldn't do it in in the in the in a
年随机线性代数有
year so randomized linear algebra has
突然出现了那个想法
popped up and that the idea there which
将看到是使用概率进行抽样
will see is to use probability to sample
矩阵并与您的样品一起使用
the matrix and work with your samples so
如果矩阵是合理的，它不是
if the matrix is reasonably it is not is
太大了但不太疯狂所以
too way too big but not too crazy so to
那么你可以对列进行采样
speak then you could sample the columns
和行，并得到一个答案
and the rows and get a an answer from
样本看我是否对列进行采样
the sample see if I sample the columns
矩阵的我得到这样的东西
of a matrix I'm getting something so
说什么是抽样意味着让我公正
said what is sampling mean let me just
完成这个说再添加一点
complete this say say add add a little
对于这个矩阵样本，我有一个
to this sample of matrix so I have a
当然，巨型矩阵可能很稀疏
giant matrix a might be sparse of course
我没有分辨那里稀疏
I didn't distinguish over there sparse
事情会是另一件事，如果
things that would be another thing so if
我只是随机X随机X的更多
I just take a random X random X's more
比一个但不是完整的n维度
than one but not the full n dimensions
那些会给我随机的人
those will give me random guys in the
列空间和矩阵是否合适
column space and if the matrix is kind
合理的那些会给我它
of reasonable those will give me it
一个漂亮的人不会花太多钱
won't take too many to have a pretty
合理的我
reasonable I
列空间是什么样的
of what that column space is like and
以及它的右侧所以这样
and with its right-hand side so so this
随机线性代数的世界有
world of randomized linear algebra has
成长，因为它必须当然
grown because it had to and of course
你任何声明，它永远不会说
you any statement it can never say for
确定你会得到正确的答案
sure you're gonna get the right answer
但是，但是使用不等式
but but but so using the inequalities of
你可以经常这么说的概率
probability you can often say that
你有机会离开了
you're the chance of being way off is
你知道不到二分之一到二十分之一
you know less than one in two to the 20s
或类似的东西，所以答案是
or something so so the answer is in
现实你得到的是你得到的好
reality you you get that you get a good
回答没问题，就像结束了这一点
answer okay that is like the end of this
第二章第四点所以在这里，这是
chapter two point four so here this is
所有第二章都是迭代的
all chapter two really the the iterative
方法一所有极本
methods in to one all that most of this
在两点两大是两点
is in two point two big is two point
三，然后真的很大是随机的
three and then really big is randomized
在两点四好，所以现在在哪里
in two point four okay so now where are
我们
we
如果你要告诉我或不知道
you're going to let me know or not if
这对C很有用，但你有点儿
this is useful the C but you're sort of
你有点看到现实生活中的东西
you sort of see what what are real-life
问题，当然我们是高度的
problems and of course we're highly
在获得该特别感兴趣
especially interested in getting to the
深入学习的例子
deep learning examples which are
不确定是的，那么当你的时候
underdetermined yeah then when you're
在确定你已经得到了很多
under determined you've got many
解决方案和问题是哪一个
solutions and the question is which one
是一个很好的，并深入学习我
is a good one and in deep learning I
只是我无法抗拒说一句话
just I can't resist saying another word
你希望有很多解决方案
you hope so there are many solutions
如何做好你的选择一些
what to do well your your pick some
像最速下降的算法
algorithm like steepest descent which is
找到一个解决方案让你如愿
going to find a solution so you're like
你希望它是一个好的，什么是一个
you hope it's a good one and what is a
好的意思是经文不好
good one mean verses are not good one
他们都是解决方案的好方法
they're all solutions a good one means
当你将它应用于测试时
that when you apply it to the test
你还没有看到的数据
data that you haven't yet seen it gives
对您的测试数据有良好的效果
good results on the test data you've
确实解决方案已经学会了
really the solution has learned
来自训练数据的东西和它
something from the training data and it
处理测试数据，这就是
works on the test data so that's the the
在深度学习如何大问题
the big question in deep learning how
你这样做是否真的发生了？
does it happen that you by doing
梯度下降或任何算法
gradient descent or whatever algorithm
该算法如何偏向于
how does that algorithm sort of bias the
解决方案它被称为隐式偏见如何
solution it's called implicit bias how
该算法是否偏向于解决方案
does that algorithm bias a solution
朝着一个解决方案的方向发展
toward one toward a solution that's that
推广适用于测试数据和
generalizes that works on test data and
你可以想到哪些算法会
you can think of algorithms which would
让它接近一个没有的解决方案
give it approach a solution that did not
处理测试数据，这就是你
work on test data so that's what you
想要远离你想要的那些
want to stay away from you want the ones
那工作所以有非常深刻的数学
that work so there's very deep math
问题有其惟一知道
questions there which are kind of knew
他们并没有出现，直到他们没有和
they didn't arise until they did and
会尽量节省一些什么什么
will try to save some of what's what's
被理解为好，我现在可以关注
being understood okay can I focus now on
对于剩下今天在这休息
for the rest the rest of today on this
矩阵几乎是单数的情况
case when the matrix is nearly singular
所以你可以应用消除但它
so you could apply elimination but it
会产生糟糕的结果，但那么
would give a poor result but so the then
一种解决方案是好耶
one solution is well yeah
一个解决方案是我提到的SVD
one solution is the SVD I only mentioned
这里的SVD作为一个算法，但
the SVD here as an algorithm but of
当然这是SVD会给你的
course it is the SVD would give you
给你一个答案的男孩在哪里
gives you gives you an answer boy where
如果这已经过得很好了
should that have gone well space over
这里的SVD让你产生
here the SVD so that produces you you
有一个相同的西格玛V转置和
have a equal u Sigma V transpose and
那么逆是VSigma逆u
then a inverse is V Sigma inverse u
转置没关系
transpose okay
所以我们在这里谈论我们
so we're in the case here we're talking
关于五号几乎奇异的地方
about number five nearly singular where
西格玛有一些非常小的单数
Sigma has some very small singular
价值然后Sigma反转有一些非常
values then Sigma inverse has some very
大的奇异值，所以这就是你
big singular values so this is you're
真的是野生的狂野领地
really in kind of wild wild territory
这里有非常大的反转所以
here with with very big inverses so that
这会是一种方法，但是
would that would be one way to do it but
这是一种规范化的方法
this is a this is a way to regularize
这个问题让我们注意一下
the problem so let's just pay attention
到还好还好所以我想尽量减少
to that okay okay so suppose I minimize
斧头减去B平方和Delta的总和
the sum of ax minus B squared and Delta
平方乘以x平方的大小
squared times the size of x squared and
我将使用L2标准是会
I'm going to use the l2 norm it's gonna
至少是一个花生
be at least squares a peanut least
有惩罚的广场当然是这样的
squares with penalty so of course it's
这里的l2规范-是的，好吧，我想
the l2 norm here - yep okay suppose I
为我选择的一些人解决这个问题
solve that for a delta for some I choose
我必须选择一个积极的三角洲
I have to choose a delta a positive
三角洲和我选择积极的三角洲
Delta and when I choose a positive Delta
然后我有一个可解决的问题
then I have a solvable problem
即使这变为零或一个
even if this goes to zero or a does
疯狂的事情这会让我感到高兴
crazy things this is going to keep me
实际上远离单数的方程式
away from singular in fact what equation
这会导致这是至少
does that lead to so that's a least
正方形问题，额外罚款
squares problem with an extra penalty
因为它会来，我想是的
term so it would come I suppose let's
看看我是否将方程写为deltaIx
see if I write the equations a delta I x
等于B0可能是最少的
equals B 0 maybe that is the least
平方方程式通常正常
squares equation the usual normal
对此的等式
equation for this
增强系统，因为有什么
augmented system because what's the
错误在这里这是一个新的大aa明星
error here this is the new big a a star
让我们说X等于这是新的B所以
let's say X equals this is the new B so
如果我应用最小二乘法来做什么
if I apply least-squares to that what do
我尽量减少方格和我的总和
I do I minimize the sum of squares and I
所以我最不正常
so I'm in so least squares would
最小化ax减去B平方即可
minimize ax minus B squared that would
是来自第一个组件和
be the from the first components and
Delta从最后一个平方x平方
Delta squared x squared from the last
组件正是我们所说的
component which is exactly what we said
我们这样做的方式是这样的
we were doing so in a way this is the
看到那个惩罚的等式
equation that saw that the penalty
方法正在解决，问题是如此
method is solving and the question is so
一个问题很自然就是看什么
one question natural is watch what's
你的DeltaB那就是那个问题
your Delta B well that's that questions
今天超越我们，这是一个平衡
beyond us today that it's it's a balance
你怎么相信和多少
of how what you can believe and how much
噪音在系统和一切
noise is in the system and everything
我们可以问的是Delta的选择
yeah choice of Delta what we could ask
是数学问题会发生什么
is the math question what happens as
Delta变为0所以假设我解决了这个问题
Delta goes to 0 so suppose I solve this
问题让我看看我能写出来
problem let's see I could write it
不同，我会在那里写什么
differently shall I write there what
这部分就是这里的等式
would be the equation here this part
会给我们a转置a然后
would give us the a transpose a and then
这部分会给我们带来的
this part would give us just the
身份x等于转置BI思考
identity x equals a transpose B I think
是的，那不是我真的
yeah wouldn't that be so really I've
这里写的是一个明星
written here what that is is a star
转移这是最不明智的明星
transpose a star that this is least
在这个广场给它给出了
squares on this gives it gives that
因此所有这些都是等价的
equation so all of those are equivalent
所有这些都是等价的
all of those would be equivalent
陈述什么惩罚问题
statements of what the penalized problem
是你在解决，然后是
is that you're solving and then the
问题是Delta达到了什么
question is as Delta goes to 0 what
当然发生在你什么时候
happens of course something you're when
Delta达到0你就是在堕落
Delta goes to 0 you're you're falling
在悬崖上有点东西
off the cliff something something quite
不同它突然发生了
different it's suddenly going to happen
也许我们甚至可以理解
there maybe we could even understand
这个问题有一个1比1的矩阵
this this question with a 1 by 1 matrix
是的我觉得这部分以a开头
yeah I think this section starts with a
1比1假设a只是一个数字没关系
1 by 1 suppose a is just a number okay
也许我会把它放在这个板上
maybe I'll just put that on this board
这里假设a只是一个数字那么
here suppose a is just a number so what
我该怎么拨打该号码时只需一
am I gonna call that number just one by
让我称之为Sigma，因为它是
one let me call it Sigma because it's
当然是领先的奇异价值
certainly the leading singular value
好吧那么我的等式是什么
okay so so what's my equation that I'm
解决转置问题将是西格玛
solving a transpose a would be Sigma
广场加三角洲广场一个接一个X.
square plus Delta square one by one X
我应该给一些标在这里我
should I give some subscript here I
应该真的这样做是对的
should really to do it right this is the
给定Delta和我的解决方案
solution for a given Delta and I'm
询问发生了什么，以便解决
asking what happened so that solution
这个矩阵肯定会存在
will exist fine this matrix is certainly
可逆的是半正定的
invertible that's positive semi definite
至少那是积极的半明确的
at least that's positive semi definite
那么delta的平方怎么样呢
and what about delta squared i it is
正定当然只是
positive definite of course just the
与一个因素的身份所以这是一个
identity with a factor so this is a
正定矩阵它在那里我
positive definite matrix it's there i
当然有一个解决方案，让我
certainly have a solution and let me
继续这个逐个案例
keep going on this one by one case this
将是一个转移a只是一个西格玛我
would be a transfer a is just a sigma i
认为这只是sigmapokay所以这是
think it's just sigma p okay so this is
a是一个接一个，有两个案例
a is one by one and there are two cases
这里西格玛大于零或西格玛
here sigma bigger than zero or sigma
等于零
equals zero
在任何一种情况下，我只是想
and in either case we I just want to
知道什么是限制所以答案X
know what's the limit so so the answer X
是啊，让我再右手
yeah let me just take the right hand
侧
side
不，那很好，所以我也好
no that's fine yep okay so am i
竞争好吧使用惩罚
competing okay the using the penalized
关于你一个接一个问题的事情
thing on a one by one problem which you
可以说是那种有点小
could say is kind of a little bit small
为了解决这个等式或
for so solving this equation or
等价地减少这个，所以我就是我
equivalently minimizing this so I'm I'm
在这里，我发现了最低限度
here I'm finding the minimum of a was
SigmaX减去B平方加Delta
Sigma X minus B squared plus Delta
平方x平方我是因为我希望
squared x squared I'm because I'm hoping
如果我发现你看到它只是
that if I found that you see it's just
一个接一个只是一个数字，我希望
one by one just a number and I'm hoping
如果计算微积分会同意
that if calculate calculus will agree
这里有线性代数，如果我找到的话
with linear algebra here that if I find
这个的最小值让我写下来
the minimum of this so let me write it
Sigma平方x平方和Delta
out Sigma squared x squared and Delta
平方x平方然后减去2西格玛
squared x squared and then minus 2 Sigma
XB然后加B平方，现在我
X B and then plus B squared and now I'm
要找到最小的意思
going to find the minimum which means
我将导数设置为0，所以得到2
I'd set the derivative to 0 so I get 2
Sigma得到了平方，我获得了2个Delta平方
Sigma squared and 2 Delta squared I get
a2在这里，这给了我X.
a 2 here and this gives me the X
衍生物是2西格玛B，所以我得到2
derivative is 2 Sigma B so I get a 2
在那里，我很好，我刚刚取消了两个
there and I'm ok I just cancelled both
两个，这就是我的等式
the twos and that's the equation so I
可以解决方程X是SigmaB
can solve that equation X is Sigma B
西格玛超过Sigma平方加上Delta
Sigma over Sigma squared plus Delta
平方B所以这真的是我的数量
squared B so it's really that quantity I
想让Delta再次走到0那么
want to let Delta go to 0 so again what
我在这里干什么我走我一个1×1
am I doing here I'm taking a 1 by 1
例子只是为了看看会发生什么
example just to see what happens in the
限制
limit
作为sigma-delta对不起Delta达到0
as sigma-delta sorry Delta goes to 0
发生了什么，所以我只需要看看
what happens so I just have to look at
这个东西的限制是什么？
that what is the limit of that thing in
当Delta达到0时就是一个圆圈
a circle as Delta goes to 0 that's so
我发现了一个接一个的问题
I'm finding out for a one by one problem
什么是惩罚最小二乘问题
what a penalized least squares problem
岭回归可能遍布整个世界
Ridge regression could all over the
把发生的事情确定，所以会发生什么
place what happens ok so what happens to
这个数字随着Delta变为01而过
that number as Delta goes to 0 1 over
西格玛所以现在三角洲变为0所以
Sigma so now the Delta go to 0 so that
因为，超过Sigma的方法是1
approaches 1 over Sigma right because
Delta消失，Sigma超过Sigma
Delta disappears and Sigma over Sigma
平均1超过Sigma，所以它接近
squared 1 over Sigma so it approaches
相反，但另一个是什么
the inverse but but what's the other
可能性在这里另一种可能性
possibility here the other possibility
西格玛是0
is that Sigma is 0
我没有说这个矩阵是否是1
I didn't say whether this matrix is 1 by
如果Sigma，1个矩阵是否可逆
1 matrix was invertible or not if Sigma
不是0然后我在Sigma上1到1
is not 0 then I go to 1 over Sigma if
Sigma非常小，需要一段时间
Sigma is really small it'll take a while
达美必须要小一点
Delta will have to get small small small
甚至与Sigma相比直到
even compared to Sigma until till
最后这个词就消失了，我只是
finally that term goes away and I'm just
有一个超过西格玛，但如果西格玛是0
have 1 over Sigma but what if Sigma is 0
对不起感到兴奋0谁也
sorry to get excited about 0 who would
兴奋的0好，所以这就是
get excited about 0 ok so this is the
如果西格玛是西格玛，则为1
case when this is 1 over Sigma if Sigma
是积极的，如果，它会接近什么
is positive and what does it approach if
Sigma为00因为它会为0
Sigma is 0 0 because this is 0 it will
整个问题就像消失了
the whole problem was like disappeared
这里西格玛是0这里是西格玛所以
here the Sigma was 0 here's a Sigma so
无论如何
anyway
西格玛将是西格玛是0而我是
Sigma will be if Sigma is 0 and I'm
总是0，但我有一个
getting 0 all the time but I have a
体面的问题，因为德尔
decent problem because the del
-平方在那里我有一个体面的
- squared is there I have a decent
问题直到最后一刻我的问题
problem until the last minute my problem
分崩离析Delta变为0，我有一个
falls apart Delta goes to 0 and I have a
零等于零问题我迷失了但是
zero equals zero problem I'm lost but
关键是惩罚让我保持
the point is the penalty kept me
积极让我保持这个三角洲的平方
positive kept me with this Delta squared
直到最后一个关键时刻为止
term until the last critical moment even
即使那样，它也让我保持积极的态度
it kept me positive even if that was
零如果为零，则为零
zero if that is zero and this is zero I
还有什么东西在这里，所以我还是
still have something here so I still
有问题需要解决，有什么问题
have a problem to solve and what's the
如果西格玛是，则限制为1
limit then so a 1 over Sigma if Sigma is
积极的，如果西格玛，答案是什么？
positive and what's the answer if Sigma
不是肯定的，只是告诉我它是0
is not positive it's 0 just tell me it's
再次，我得到0，我得到0全部
again I'm getting 0 well I get 0 all the
方式，我在限制中得到0，现在让
way and I get 0 in the limit and now let
我只想问我在这里得到了什么
me just ask what have I got here what
这突如其来的分叉是什么？
what is this this sudden bifurcation
这才是我认识到的
that's what's the do I recognize this
限制中的倒数为Delta
the the inverse in the limit as Delta
如果是，那么转到0对于Sigma是1
goes to 0 is either 1 over Sigma if it's
如果这是有道理的
if that makes sense
或0表示不超过1段
or at 0 which is not like 1 over segment
Sigma超过Sigma1，而Sigma则为0
1 over Sigma as Sigma goes to 0 the
事这件事情变得越来越大，
thing this thing is getting bigger and
大
bigger
但在西格玛等于0的0你看
but at Sigma equals 0 its 0 you see
这真的是一种奇怪的
that's a really that's a strange kind of
一个极限，现在是什么词
a limit and what word now it would be
我在这里找到了什么
over there what have I found here in
这个限制你说再说一遍，因为
this limit you say say it again because
这是完全正确的有
it was exactly right there's
伪逆所以这个这个系统
pseudo-inverse so this this this system
选择大于零的Delta然后
choose Delta greater than zero then
三角洲要去0解决方案去
Delta are going to 0 the solution goes
到伪逆
to the pseudo-inverse
这就是关键时刻
that's the key fact that that is when
达美实在是真的很小
Delta is really really small then this
如果达美，那就表现得非常疯狂
behaves in a pretty crazy way if Delta
真的很小，然后
is really really small then and then
如果是Sigma，Sigma会更大或者它是零
Sigma is bigger or it's zero if it's
如果它是零，那你走的就越大
bigger you go this way if it's zero you
走那条路就是这就是消息
go that way so that's that's the message
而且这还有的惩罚这些
and that this there's penalized these
随着惩罚的到来，方块接近
squares approaches as the penalty gets
越来越小的接近
smaller and smaller approaches the
正确回答总是正确的答案
correct answer the always correct answer
零和之间的分裂突然
with that sudden split between zero and
不是我们与之相关的零
not zero that we associate with the
伪逆当然是一个
pseudo-inverse yeah of course in a
你试图找到的实际案例
practical case you're trying to find the
a中的电阻和电感
the resistances and inductances in a
通过尝试电路和电路
circuit by trying the circuit and
看着输出B并搞清楚
looking at the output B and figuring out
什么输入什么是如此未知
what input what what the so the unknown
X是未知系统
X is the is the unknown system
参数电压而不是
parameters the voltage and not the
电压和电流，但但
voltage and current but the but the
电阻和电感
resistance and inductance and
电容好，所以现在我只有
capacitance okay so that's now I've only
事实证明，你在一个接一个的情况下
proved that in the one by one case you
可能会说这不是一个证据
may say that's not much of a proof in
我们可以一个接一个地看到它
the one by one case we could see it
发生在我们眼前
happen in front of our eyes
所以真的一步我没有带到这里
so really step I haven't taken here is
完成任何矩阵a
to complete that to any matrix a so
这就是声明
that's the statement then that's the
声明
statement
所以这是任何或任何的陈述
so that's the statement for any or any
矩阵a这个矩阵a转置A加
matrix a this matrix a transpose A plus
Delta平方反转时间为转置
Delta squared inverse times a transpose
这是我们的解决方案矩阵
that's the solution matrix to our
问题是的，这就是我写的
problem right yep that's what I wrote
在那里我采取反向和弹出
down up there I take the inverse and pop
它在那里接近加号
it over there that approaches a plus the
伪逆，这就是我们刚刚
pseudo inverse and that's what we just
逐个检查这一点
checked for one by one one by one this
西格玛超过Sigma平方加上Delta
was Sigma over Sigma squared plus Delta
平方，它到了1结束
squared and it went to either to 1 over
西格玛或它在0分裂它的限制
Sigma or to 0 it split in the limit it
表明限制是微妙的
shows that limits are can be delicate
你知道Delta达到0时的极限
you know the limit as Delta goes to 0
这件事突然间断了
this thing it suddenly discontinuous
这是它那这个号码
it's it's it's this number that's
成长，然后突然在0下降
growing and then suddenly at 0 it falls
无论如何，回到0将是
back to 0 anyway that would be the
声明实际上是统计学家
statement actually statisticians
发现了伪逆像
discovered the pseudo inverse like
独立于线性代数历史
independently of linear algebra history
这是因为统计学家确实做到了
of it because statisticians did exactly
那要规范他们的问题
that to regularize the problem they
介绍了一个惩罚并与之合作
introduced a penalty and worked with
这个矩阵所以统计学家就是这样的
this matrix so so statisticians were the
首先要看到，是的想到
first to see that that yeah to think of
这是一个很自然的事情
that as a natural thing to do in in a
罚款的实际案例好吧所以我
practical case at a penalty okay so I
猜这是增加一个惩罚但是
guess so this is adding a penalty but
记住，我们留下了L两个规范
remember that we stayed with L two norms
我们可以保持l2最小二乘
staying with l2 least-squares we could
问问发生了什么
ask what happens yeah
假设罚款是l1标准
suppose the penalty is the l1 norm
假设我最小化我不能做到这一点
suppose I minimize I'm not up to do this
今天
today
假设我最小化，也许让我们说
suppose I minimize that maybe let's say
我会做l2，但我会做点球员
I'll do l2 but I'll do the penalty guy
在l1规范中，我猜我不是，我是
in the l1 norm I guess I'm not yeah I'm
当然不是那个或你的专家
certainly not an expert on that or you
甚至可以认为这样的力量
could even think just that power so that
会有一个统计学家的名字
would have a name that statisticians a
统计学家发明了它的名字
statistician invented this it's called
在l1规范中的套索，这是一个很大的
the lasso in the l1 norm and it's a big
处理像l1规范那样的雪决定
deal snow decisions like the l1 norm
因为它真的因为它
because because it really because it
给出了给你的稀疏解决方案
gives sparse solutions it gives you give
没有一个更真实的解决方案
sort of more genuine solutions without a
一大堆在一点一点的组件
whole lot of little little components in
答案是的，所以这是一个
the answer yep so that this was an
重要的一步，所以也许让我只是
important step and so maybe let me just
再说一遍，我们就是那么大的地方
say again we're where we are in that big
列出两个重要的
list the the the the two important ones
我没有做过但这些都是
that I haven't done yet are these
2.1中的迭代方法就是这样的
iterative methods in 2.1 so that's like
传统的线性代数就是如何
conventional linear algebra just how to
处理一个大矩阵可能与一些
deal with a big matrix maybe with some
特殊结构是线性的
special structure that's what linear
代数是数值线性代数
algebra is numerical linear algebra is
所有关于然后克-施密特与或
all about and then gram-schmidt with or
没有旋转，这是一个主力
without pivoting which is a workhorse of
数值计算，我想我
of numerical computing and I think I
最好保存下次
better save that for next time
所以这就是那个
so so this is the one
在这个时候挑选，我们看到了什么
picked for this time and we saw what
发生在l2井，我们看到了一个
happened in l2 well we saw it for one by
你想扩展一个证明吗？
one would you want to extend to prove
这对于任何超越一个一个
this for any a going beyond one by one
你怎么会为任何人证明这样的事情
how would you prove such a thing for any
我想我不会这样做的
a I guess I'm I'm not going to do it it
这太痛苦但是你怎么样？
it's too painful but but how would you
如果你愿意，你可以使用SVD
do it you would use the SVD if you want
证明关于矩阵的一些东西
to prove something about matrices about
任何矩阵SVD都是你最好的东西
any matrix the SVD is the best thing you
可以拥有你可以拥有的最好的工具
could have the best tool you could have
我可以用SVDI来写这个
I can write this in terms of the SVD I
只需插入即可插入等号
just plug in I just plug in a equals
无论SVD告诉我什么
whatever the SVD tells me to put in
在那里你使用SigmaVtranspose插入它
there you Sigma V transpose plug it in
使用这个事实简化了它
there simplify it using the fact that
这些是正交的你知道我总是
these are orthogonal you know I always
如果我有任何好运，我会得到的
if I have any good luck it'll I'll get
从那里到某个地方的身份
an identity somewhere from there and an
identity somewhere from there and it'll
所有简化它都将对角化
all simplify it'll all diagonalize
这就是在SVD确实这
that's what the SVD really does this
把我凌乱的问题变成一个问题
turns my messy problem into a problem
关于他们的对角矩阵西格玛
about their diagonal matrix Sigma in the
中间所以我不妨把西格玛放进去
middle so I might as well put Sigma in
中间是的，为什么不在我们给予之前
the middle yeah why not before we give
在它上面
up on it
一个特例，但真的
a special case of that but the really
真实的情况就是a
the genuine case would be when a is
SigmaSigma转换Sigma加Delta
Sigma Sigma transpose Sigma plus Delta
平方i反转时间Sigma转置
squared i inverse times Sigma transpose
接近伪逆Sigma加
approaches the pseudo inverse Sigma plus
而这一点就是矩阵西格玛
and the point is the matrix Sigma here
是对角线哦，我几乎在那里
is diagonal and oh I'm practically there
实际上为什么我接近于存在
actually why am i close to being being
能够很好地阅读这一切
able to read this off well everything is
对角线对角线对角线
diagonal here diagonal diagonal diagonal
以及那些对角线上发生了什么
and what's happening on those diagonal
条目，所以你不得不接受我的话
entries so you had to take my word that
当我插入SVD的U和
when I plugged in the SVD the U and the
V有点被分开了
V kind of got got separated out to the
最左边和最右边，它是
far left and the far right and it was
这是住在中部所以它的
that that stayed in the middle so it's
真的，这是它的核心和方式
really this is the heart of it and how
你认为这是一个对角线吗？
do you suppose so that's a diagonal
矩阵所以我只是看看会发生什么
matrix so I'm just looking what happens
在每个对角线入口和哪个问题
on each diagonal entry and which problem
这是什么问题
is that well the the question of what's
发生在一个典型的对角线入口
happening on a typical diagonal entry of
这件事是什么问题的
this thing is is what question the
一个接一个的案子现在一个接一个，因为
one-by-one case now one by one because
对角线中的每个条目都不均匀
each entry in the diagonal is not even
注意到其他人是的，所以那就是
noticing the others yeah so so that's
逻辑，它将在笔记中
the logic and it would be in the notes
首先逐一证明它
prove it first for one by one and
其次是对角线，最后是对角线
secondly for diagonal this and finally
对于A和他们正在使用SVD
for with A's and they're using the SVD
和你一起被转换成两个来获得
with you and be transposed to two to get
走开，带我们回到这里
out of the way and bring us back to here
好吧这是理论，但真的是II
okay so that's the theory but really I I
我想我的想法最多
guess I'm thinking that far the most
今天的重要信息
important thing message in today's
讲座在这个不同的列表中
lecture is in this list of different
出现的问题类型和
types of problems that appear and
与他们和我们合作的不同方式
different ways to work with them and we
还没有完成克施密特
haven't done gram-schmidt and that will
是的，我们还没有这样做
be and we haven't done it eration so
这是我作为一个这一章
this is I'm kind of this chapter as a
比的调查以及更多的调查
survey of well more than a survey of
什么数值线性代数是关于
what numerical linear algebra is about
而且我还没有做过随机而我很抱歉
and I haven't done random yet I'm sorry
这是未来-所以三块是
that's coming - so three pieces are
still to come but let's take the last
还是要来，但让我们拿走最后一个
两分钟，并称它为一天
two minutes off and call it a day